Now lets take a look at a simplified version of the Berkley paradox
现在我们以伯克利大学两个院系的录取情况为例
with only two departments.
简要讲解辛普森悖论的形成
As you can see more men applied to to department A than department B and
可以看到 申请 A 院系的男生人数多于 B 院系
vice versa for women.
女生的申请情况则恰恰相反
Now if I calculate the percentage of men who were accepted to department
现在计算 A 院系男生的录取率 为 62%
A I get 62% and if I do the same for women, I get 82%.
女生的录取率为 82%
So acceptance is fairly high and more women are accepted.
这表明该院系的录取率很高 而且录取的女生人数较多
Now if I do the same for
然后计算 B 院系的各项录取率
department B I get that the overall acceptance rate is lower but
发现总体录取率较低
still more women were accepted than men as a percentage of the applicants.
不过同申请率相比 被录取的女生人数依然比男生多
However now let's look at the total numbers of men and women who applied and
但是 再看看两个院系申请及招收的
were accepted across both departments.
男女生总数
Overall, a greater percentage of men have been accepted than women.
就总体而言 男生的录取率远高于女生
How can this happen?
为什么会这样？
Like Kary said, the explanation is that more women applied to department B,
正如 Kary 所言 这是因为申请 B 院系的女生人数更多
which has a lower acceptance rate.
而该院系的录取率又很低
So that a lower percentage of women are accepted overall.
从而导致女生的整体录取率较低
Now the actual Berkeley data was more complicated than this.
事实上 伯克利大学的调查数据远比这复杂得多
There were more than two departments, and
学校招生院系不止两个
in some departments men had a higher acceptance rate than women.
其中某些院系的男生录取率高于女生
But not a statistically significant difference, and
不过高出的百分比不具有统计显著性
most departments had a small but significant bias in favor of women.
绝大多数院系的女生录取率略微比男生高 而且具有显著性
Now, how can this apply to AB testing?
那么这又是如何应用到 AB 测试中的？
Well, you could see the same sort of think happen for click through rate.
你会发现 同样的思路也会出现在点击率的计算中
Where if you look at your total or aggregate experiment results, then
分析实验组的总数或将实验组结果合并后
the experiment group has a lower click through rate than the control group.
算得的实验组点击率低于对照组
But then if you break it down by new users and
但是分别分析新用户和资深用户的情况
experienced users, you see the reverse.
又得到相反的结论
How could this happen?
这是怎么回事？
Actually, I want you to fill in the numbers.
事实上 我希望你能填出算得的点击率
You should be able to use a similar strategy to the Berkeley example.
你应该使用与伯克利实例相似的分析策略
Once you're done, you can take a minute to think about what those results would
填写完毕后 仔细想想这些数据意味着什么
mean but while you're coming up with the numbers
不过在计算过程中
don't worry too much about how plausible they are.
不用考虑所得数据是否合理
Fill in any numbers such that the click through rate is higher in the experiment
如果实验组新用户和资深用户的点击率均高于对照组
group than the control group for both new and experienced users.
请如实填写数据
But overall, the click through rate is lower in the experiment group.
但是 实验组整体的点击率较低
You only need to fill in these two rows but if you also want to fill in
你只需填写这两行 不过如果你想记录计算过程
the total row to help keep track of your work you can do that too.
也可以填写总数一行